Hudson Bailey

Researcher & Writer

hudsonbailey.org || 610.755.5471 h@hudsonbailey.org || Chicago IL

SUMMARY

Resourceful and adaptable technical writer with research background spanning life sciences and social sciences

Generalist and collaborator adept at bridging communication and achieving results in diverse and multi-disciplinary teams

Strategic technologist with experience developing writing automation scripts and workflows

EDUCATION

M.A. University of Chicago Social Sciences

Full-Tuition Scholarship

B.A. Oberlin College

Neuroscience

SKILLS

Research:

research design, project management, data collection, semi-structured interviews, transcription, semiotics, statistical analysis, participant observation

Research Tools:

spreadsheets (G/MS/Libre), QGIS, SPSS, numpy, pandas

Writing Tools:

Sublime, Markdown, Pandoc, LaTeX, RegEx, Git, word processors (MS/G/Libre)

Scripting & Development:

Python, Bash, Git, Java

EXPERIENCE

Zises Communications - Dispensary33

Chicago IL

Research & Grant Writing Consultant | Aug 2019 - present

- Plan, write and edit applications for competitive cannabis business licenses in multiple states (medical and recreational)
- Organize research of state and federal laws in one of the most complex, dynamic and highly-regulated industries
- GIS analysis for business development and zoning compliance

Self-Employed

Chicago IL & Remote

Academic Tutor, Technical Writer, Editor || Feb 2016 - present

- Copy-edit, proof-read, fact-check industry- and popular-audience articles about technology
- Ghostwrite scientific articles, industry white papers
- Tutor undergraduate, professional and returning students in essay writing, symbolic logic, and graduate test prep (GRE)

Anthropology Department – University of Chicago

Chicago IL

Graduate Student Researcher | Sept 2016 - Aug 2017

- Conducted seven months of qualitative ethnographic research on the use of mobile apps, machine learning and 'digital phenotyping' in psychiatry
- Studied cultural, economic and institutional structures guiding technology development in psychiatry
- Organized, conducted, transcribed and analyzed in-depth interviews and discussions with psychiatrists, data scientists, neuroscientists and entrepreneurs

CoNeCt Lab - University of Illinois at Chicago

Chicago IL

VR Technology Consultant || July - Oct 2016

• Facilitated early-stage 'virtual reality' project design for experimental Anorexia and Body Dysmorphic Disorder exposure therapies

Kwakye Multisensory Integration Lab - Oberlin College

Oberlin OH

Research Assistant || Sept 2013 - July 2015

- Designed and developed of 'virtual reality' research application for studying how human visual and auditory systems interact at physiological and behavioral levels
- Managed participant-facing laboratory operations including recruitment, scheduling, correspondence. study moderation, debriefing
- Updated lab data management practices and streamlined data analysis programs to integrate data across multiple concurrent studies
- Presented research findings at the Society for Neuroscience conference and community-oriented symposium on synesthesia
- First author on published paper: Bailey, H. D., Mullaney, A. B., Gibney, K. D., & Kwakye, L. D. (2018). Audiovisual integration varies with target and environment richness in immersive virtual reality. Multisensory Research, 31(7), 689 713. doi:10.1163/22134808-20181301

Anthropology Department – Oberlin College

Oberlin OH

Research Assistant || Feb – June 2015

- Conducted background research for professor's book on military-environment complex, environmental science and war in Iraq
- Prepared literature reviews on technical topics in environmental economics and systems ecology
- Exhaustive media analysis of military activities and environmental projects
- · Social network analysis identifying actors, connections and cash flow

Philosophy Department – Oberlin College

Oberlin OH

Teaching Assistant | Sept 2013 - Dec 2014

• Graded assignments and tutored students in Symbolic Logic philosophy course

Last updated Oct 22, 2019